National Capital Area Chapter American Society for Public Administration 013
People's Archive, MLK Library
National Capital Area Chapter American Society for Public Administration Records
1986-1991
People's Archive, MLK Library
American Society for Public Administration. National Capital Area Chapter
013
11 Linear feet
22 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: Presidential papers, 1985-1989 (3 linear ft.) This series contains Michael Carmichael's presidential papers arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material. It includes budgets, correspondence, the ASPA's constitution, conference materials, budgets, membership lists, handbooks, newsletters, and other topics. ASPA information and annual conference materials appear at the end of the series. Series 2: Office files, 1978-1991 (4 linear ft.) This series contains the ASPA's office files arranged alphabetically by topic. The files include by-laws, some annual reports, Society Conference materials (1978-1991), expense vouchers, meeting minutes, newsletters, financial reports, and handbooks (1984-1989). The series also contains five audiotapes of 1984 conference presentations. Series 3: Treasurer's records, 1984-1988 This series includes bank statements, bank vouchers, and financial reports.
Biographical / Historical
The National Capital Area Chapter is one of the largest chapters of the American Society for Public Administration (ASPA). Its members include public servants, academics, and students in Washington, D.C. The Chapter developed the professional journal, the Bureaucrat. ASPA was founded in 1939 to promote effectiveness in government, professionalism, and innovation among public administration.
Custodial History
John Stone and Michael Carmichael, former officers of the National Capital Area Chapter American Society for Public Administration, donated the records in 1988 and 1989.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes budgets, financial statements, membership information, newsletters, handbooks, conference materials, annual reports, and meeting minutes from the National Capital Area Chapter American Society for Public Administration's office files and past officers of the Society.
Societies and clubs; Public administration; Organizational Records; Minutes (Records); Newsletters
- Series 1: Presidential papers, 1985-1989
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains Michael Carmichael's presidential papers arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material. It includes budgets, correspondence, the Society's constitution, conference materials, budgets, membership lists, handbooks, newsletters, and other topics. National Society information and annual conference materials appear at the end of the series.
  - Administrative Procedures, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual report, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Awards, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Award reception, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board minutes/agendas, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Budget and finance, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Budget and finance, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - COMPA, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - NCAC Comm. Sheet, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Conference, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Special Note, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Conference reference materials, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Conference materials, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Constitution, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - D.C. group, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Elections, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Executive director, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Events listing, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Luncheons, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Medina lectures, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Member survey, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Membership, List of Activities, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Membership Development Kit, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Membership, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Membership meeting, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Newsletters, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Conference, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Conference, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Org. Liaison, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Policy issues, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Policy issues, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Proof development comm., Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Professional organizations, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Public image, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Round tables, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Sections, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Strategic PLG, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Students and student conference, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Treasurer reports, Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Volunteers, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Volunteer names, Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - National Information, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - National Information, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - National Information, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous information, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous information, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Executive Director information, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - NCAC, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - NCAC, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Annual Conference, 1985-1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Handbooks, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Series 2: Office files, 1978-1991
  Contains the Society's office files arranged alphabetically by topic. The files include the Society's by-laws, some annual reports, Society Conference materials (1978-1991), expense vouchers, meeting minutes, newsletters, financial reports, and handbooks (1984-1989). The series also contains 5 audiotapes of 1984 conference presentations.
  - Administration/management, Undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Agency Liaison network, Undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Agenda, Undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Annual reports, Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Audit, Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Awards/reception, Undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Budget, Undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Budget, Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Bureaucrat, Undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - By-laws, Undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Calendar, Undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Civil service, Undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Commemorative stamps, Undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - COMPA, Undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Conference, 1987-1991 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Conference, 1987-1991 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Conference, 1978-1986 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Conference, 1978-1986 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - D.C. Government group, Undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Directory, Undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Elections, Undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Events planning, Undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Expense vouchers, Undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Expense vouchers, Undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Finance committee, Undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Finance reports, Undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Financial reports and financial management, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Holiday reception, Undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Insurance Leadership posters, Undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Luncheon committee, Undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Medina lecture series, Undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Meeting rooms, Undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Membership committee, Undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Membership meetings, Undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of meetings, Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - National ASPA, Undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - National Council of Association for Policy Sciences, Undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - PMI, Undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Planning, Undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Nominating Committee, Undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Policy issues, Undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Post office, Undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Potomac planning, Undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - PRACADEMIC, Undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Presidents' messages, Undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Professional development committee, Undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Professional organization, Undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Public/private sector issues, Undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Public relations, Undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Retreat, Undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Roundtables, Undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Student consortium, Undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Newsletters, Undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Newsletters, Undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Stationary Samples, Undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Tax exemption, Undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Volunteer, Undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - YPI/NCAC, Undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - NCAC directory, Undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous folder, Undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Annual Report Background Information PCA, 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Leadership handbook, 1984-1989 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Leadership handbook, 1984-1989 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Leadership handbook, 1984-1989 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous items, Undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Audiocassette - Peter Edelman and Jon Herbers - Great Society Retrospective, 12/6/1984 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Audiocassette - K. Hunter et al. - 10 Years After the Congressional Budget Process, 12/6/1984 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Audiocassette - William Gregory - Space: The Last Frontier, 12/7/1984 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Audiocassette - Patterson - Closing Plenary session, 12/7/1984 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Series 3: Treasurer's records, 1984-1988
  Includes bank statements, bank vouchers, financial reports, maintained by the Society's Treasurer.
  - Bank statements/vouchers, Undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Bank statements/vouchers, Undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Bank statements/vouchers, Undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Bank statements/vouchers, Undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Bank statements/vouchers, Undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Bank statements/vouchers, Undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Voucher/Financial policy, 1984-1985 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Bank statements, Undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Financial status reports w/receipts, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Financial status reports w/receipts, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Financial status reports w/receipts, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Financial status reports w/receipt, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous papers, Undated (Box 22, Folder 2)